<?xml version="1.0"?>
<BattleSheets>
<InformationSheets>
  <BSInfo
   jName='203. OLD STOREROOM'
   jRoomDescPlayer='Boxes, crates, and barrels line the walls of this 30 &apos;x 20&apos; chamber. Spilled contents — flour, grain, broken crockery, and who knows what else — are mixed with old bones, broken furniture, splintered wood, rags, and ordure up to a depth of at least a foot. The whole area stinks of troll.'
   jRoomDescDM='The hydra&apos;s keeper, a troll, dwells here on orders from its master, the priest of the Fire Temple. Upon hearing any noise from its beast, it grabs its military fork and investigates. Those with proper identification — robes of the Fire Temple or the eight-pointed amulet — can pass, for the troll then shovesthe hydra aside and stops its heads from attacking by quick use of the weapon. The troll otherwise not only allows the beast toattack, but aids it, attacking with the weapon (which it can use long range, striking opponents up to ten feet distant and gaining a + 2 bonus to damage, due to Strength). If enemies close on it, the troll discards the weapon and attacks normally (tooth and claw). The troll&apos;s only treasure is a ring of fire resistance it wears.\n\nTroll: AC 4, MV 12&quot;, HD 6 + 6, hp 42, #AT 3, D 5-8/5-8/2-12, SA military fork (range 10&apos;, damage 3-10), SD regenerates (3 hp per round starting 3 rounds after being damaged); XP 861\n\nThe containers hold nothing valuable, all being spilled, rotted, or spoiled, save a small cask holding two gallons of fuel oil (worth about 16 gp per gallon) and a box containing 20 fresh torches.\n'
   >
  </BSInfo>
</InformationSheets>
  <BSCreature
   sCreatureName='Troll, Common'
   nAC='4'
   nACBase='4'
   jACMod='0'
   jHitPointLabel='53'
   jClassSelect='4'
   nEXP='1400'
   nHonor='-1'
   lAttacks='3'
   nHitPoints='53'
   nLevel='7'
   nToHitRank='8'
   jNotePad=''
   sDescription='﻿DESCRIPTION: Ttolls ate a common and feared humanoid on Garweeze Wurld. They come in different sizes and shapes, but most share common traits. Trolls are &quot;butt-ugly&quot;, with green, warty skin rhat is usually covered with sores of one kind or another. They have large, black eyes, short, bristly black hair, big claws and big teeth. \n\nCommon Troll: Common Trolls usually look emaciated. They rarely have clothes, armor or weapons and are appear to he only slightly above animals in their degree of civilization. However, to those &quot;in the know&quot;, these beasts have their own customs and culture.\n\n﻿COMBAT/TACTICS:Trolls regenerate 3 hit points per round and can reattach any severed limb. They cannot regenerate damage from weapons that deliver burn damage, such as fire or lightning. With their claws, they are able to climb sheer cliffs wirh an 80% chance of success. Trolls have a poor sense of hearing, but a superior sense of smell. Unless otherwise noted, Trolls have 90-foot infravision. Common Troll: Most Common Trolls have never encountered someone they could not defeat and eat. When they are hungry, which is always, they rush out to attack, overwhelming anything in their path with their raw power. Common Trolls gain +2 to-hit and inflict +4 damage with each attack due to Strength.\n'
   sSpecialAttack='N'
   sSpecialDefense='N'
   sMagicDefense='Normal'
   sPSIAttack='N'
   sPSIDefense='N'
   nBASENumAtks='1'
   nBASEMorale='10'
   nBASEMove='12'
   nBASESizeIndex='2'
   nBASEAlignmentIndex='4'
   nBASEHackFactor='1'
   nFatigueFactor='10'
   nCombatRounds='0'
   nCreatureID='1306'
   >
     <Attack
       jWeaponType='0'
       jToHitMod='2'
       jPerDiceMod='0'
       jTotalMod='4'
       jNumDice='1'
       jDiceSides='4'
       jModPenetration='0'
       jModFumble='0'
       jModCrit='0'
     >
     </Attack>
     <Attack
       jWeaponType='0'
       jToHitMod='2'
       jPerDiceMod='0'
       jTotalMod='4'
       jNumDice='1'
       jDiceSides='4'
       jModPenetration='0'
       jModFumble='0'
       jModCrit='0'
     >
     </Attack>
     <Attack
       jWeaponType='0'
       jToHitMod='2'
       jPerDiceMod='0'
       jTotalMod='4'
       jNumDice='2'
       jDiceSides='8'
       jModPenetration='0'
       jModFumble='0'
       jModCrit='0'
     >
     </Attack>
  </BSCreature>
</BattleSheets>
