<?xml version="1.0"?>
<BattleSheets>
<InformationSheets>
  <BSInfo
   jName='208. SECRET ROOM'
   jRoomDescPlayer='This bare-walled 20 &apos; square room is permeated by a feral odor. A pair of nestlike heaps of cloth and pillow lie by the east wall; bones and litter cover the floor. A large cupboard stands against the north wall. A pair of rust-red cloaks hang on pegs by the secret door, the only apparent entrance. A few pieces of dirty pewterware are on the cupboard shelves, along with two bottles of wine and a bunch of cooking herbs in a glass bottle. You notice a jumble of weapons and other items in the northwest corner.\n'
   jRoomDescDM='Two werewolves lair here. They serve the Fire Temple, bringing loot and victims to Alrrem (area 205c). The crystal sheet of area 207 is also visible here if a covering of gray cloth is pulled aside. It is a lens of transformation, actually placed here for evil purposes by luz (see Appendix C). Upon hearing noise in the adjoining room (area 207), the werewolves stand before the lens, being seen by those on the other side as angelic figures. They see through the crystal normally. If the party balks at disarming themselves, the creatures step away from the device and wait to surprise anyone entering their secret door, just in case. If the party cooperates, the monsters rush through to room 207, gather up the items left, and quickly take them to their lair. Then (and only then) do they return to room 207, in person, to deal with the (hopefully) defenseless party. Those who surrender are taken to area 206 (and then to 205). Corpses are devoured by the werewolves. The lens cannot be removed from the wall by mundane means. If a wish is used, it is either be loosened (25% chance) or shatters (75%); if the latter result occurs, luz immediately knows what happened and who did it!\n\nWerewolves (2): AC 5, MV 15&quot;, HD 4 + 3, hp 33, 28, #AT 1, D 2-8, SA if waiting in area 208, surprise on 1-3, SD hit only by silver or magic weapons; XP 370, 345 \n\nThe dirty pewterware is actually silver, 15 items worth 10-60 gp each. The bottled herbs are 18 sprigs of wolfsbane. The cupboard cabinet holds a dagger +1, a short sword + 1/ + 3 vs. lycanthropes and shapechangers, and five silver daggers, under which is a scroll of protection from lycanthropes (all) flat and upside-down, as if shelf-paper. Under a loose floor stone, found only after a careful search, is a hole containing 1, 629 sp. The pile in the corner contains various odds and ends of adventuring gear (but no food or water), plus the following.\n\n22 arrows, normal\n19 arrows, silver-tipped\n1 bow, long\n2 bows, short\n4 crossbows, light\n4 crossbow bolt cases (empty)\n82 crossbow bolts\n5 daggers\n1 flail\n1 hammer\n1 holy symbol, normal\n3 holy symbols, silvered\n1 mace\n2 mirrors, silvered\n1 morning star\n3 quivers (empty)\n3 spears\n1 sword, long\n2 swords, short\n'
   >
  </BSInfo>
</InformationSheets>
  <BSCreature
   sCreatureName='Lycanthrope: Were-Wolf#1'
   nAC='5'
   nACBase='5'
   jACMod='0'
   jHitPointLabel='42'
   jClassSelect='4'
   nEXP='420'
   nHonor='-1'
   lAttacks='3'
   nHitPoints='42'
   nLevel='5'
   nToHitRank='6'
   jNotePad=''
   sDescription='Silver or +1 weapon needed to hit.\n\nWere-WOlf in human, demi-human or humanoid form will use weapons common ro rheir occupation or class. In Were-Wolf packs, females and young encourage the adult males to attack more viciously. If a female is attacked, the malc Were-Wolf fights at +2 to. hit and does ful1 damage for each successfull blow. If young cubs are atracked, the female Were-Wolf gets +3 to-hit and does full damage. Were-Wolf cubs at 60% full gowth are 4 to-hit, those at 70% full growth are -3 ro-hit and\nso on. All Were-Wolf cubs cause 2-5 points of damage whcn they successfully land an attack.\n'
   sSpecialAttack='N'
   sSpecialDefense='N'
   sMagicDefense='Normal'
   sPSIAttack='N'
   sPSIDefense='N'
   nBASENumAtks='1'
   nBASEMorale='10'
   nBASEMove='12'
   nBASESizeIndex='2'
   nBASEAlignmentIndex='4'
   nBASEHackFactor='1'
   nFatigueFactor='10'
   nCombatRounds='0'
   nCreatureID='634'
   >
     <Attack
       jWeaponType='0'
       jToHitMod='0'
       jPerDiceMod='0'
       jTotalMod='0'
       jNumDice='1'
       jDiceSides='4'
       jModPenetration='0'
       jModFumble='0'
       jModCrit='0'
     >
     </Attack>
     <Attack
       jWeaponType='0'
       jToHitMod='0'
       jPerDiceMod='0'
       jTotalMod='0'
       jNumDice='1'
       jDiceSides='4'
       jModPenetration='0'
       jModFumble='0'
       jModCrit='0'
     >
     </Attack>
     <Attack
       jWeaponType='0'
       jToHitMod='0'
       jPerDiceMod='0'
       jTotalMod='0'
       jNumDice='2'
       jDiceSides='4'
       jModPenetration='0'
       jModFumble='0'
       jModCrit='0'
     >
     </Attack>
  </BSCreature>
  <BSCreature
   sCreatureName='Lycanthrope: Were-Wolf#2'
   nAC='5'
   nACBase='5'
   jACMod='0'
   jHitPointLabel='41'
   jClassSelect='4'
   nEXP='420'
   nHonor='-1'
   lAttacks='3'
   nHitPoints='41'
   nLevel='5'
   nToHitRank='6'
   jNotePad=''
   sDescription='Silver or +1 weapon needed to hit.\n\nWere-WOlf in human, demi-human or humanoid form will use weapons common ro rheir occupation or class. In Were-Wolf packs, females and young encourage the adult males to attack more viciously. If a female is attacked, the malc Were-Wolf fights at +2 to. hit and does ful1 damage for each successfull blow. If young cubs are atracked, the female Were-Wolf gets +3 to-hit and does full damage. Were-Wolf cubs at 60% full gowth are 4 to-hit, those at 70% full growth are -3 ro-hit and\nso on. All Were-Wolf cubs cause 2-5 points of damage whcn they successfully land an attack.\n'
   sSpecialAttack='N'
   sSpecialDefense='N'
   sMagicDefense='Normal'
   sPSIAttack='N'
   sPSIDefense='N'
   nBASENumAtks='1'
   nBASEMorale='10'
   nBASEMove='12'
   nBASESizeIndex='2'
   nBASEAlignmentIndex='4'
   nBASEHackFactor='1'
   nFatigueFactor='10'
   nCombatRounds='0'
   nCreatureID='634'
   >
     <Attack
       jWeaponType='0'
       jToHitMod='0'
       jPerDiceMod='0'
       jTotalMod='0'
       jNumDice='1'
       jDiceSides='4'
       jModPenetration='0'
       jModFumble='0'
       jModCrit='0'
     >
     </Attack>
     <Attack
       jWeaponType='0'
       jToHitMod='0'
       jPerDiceMod='0'
       jTotalMod='0'
       jNumDice='1'
       jDiceSides='4'
       jModPenetration='0'
       jModFumble='0'
       jModCrit='0'
     >
     </Attack>
     <Attack
       jWeaponType='0'
       jToHitMod='0'
       jPerDiceMod='0'
       jTotalMod='0'
       jNumDice='2'
       jDiceSides='4'
       jModPenetration='0'
       jModFumble='0'
       jModCrit='0'
     >
     </Attack>
  </BSCreature>
</BattleSheets>
