<?xml version="1.0"?>
<BattleSheets>
<InformationSheets>
  <BSInfo
   jName='234. STORAGE CHAMBER'
   jRoomDescPlayer='This oddly shaped chamber is crammed with containers of all sorts — large clay jars, boxes, barrels, crates, chests, sacks, casks, bales, bags, hampers, and others. Some are obviously broken or empty, but many seem full. Bales contain black cloth and some finished garments (cloaks, capes, kilts, etc. ). Scores of arrows, quarrels, javelins, spears, and several dozen hand weapons are in the 10&apos; x 30&apos; alcove to the northeast. At the south end of the place are boxes and several huge pottery jars, but near them are three humanoid skulls and a few bones.'
   jRoomDescDM='A su-monster lairs here, living amidst the stone flying buttresses supporting the roof of this large room. It is near the south end, and swings down to attack anyone who comes within ten feet of the south wall. It is a huge old male which recently migrated to this level from that below, having escaped its captors who kept it chained as a guard beast. Its last kill was a goblin, before that a bugbear, and its first was a half-ore; only their unbroken skulls remain to tell the tale.\n\nThe su-monster has gone hungry for some time now, as the Temple servants enter in groups and with their weapons pointed upwards. The creature has no treasure. \n\nSu-monster: AC 6, MV 9&quot;, HD 5 + 5, hp 41, #AT 5, D1-4 (x4)/2-8, SA psionics; XP 471\n\nThe alcove contains nothing magical. The many containers hold basic foodstuffs— meal, grain, flour, salt, dried and salted meats, sausages, cheese, biscuits, nuts, dried fruit, wine, ale, beer, and others.'
   >
  </BSInfo>
</InformationSheets>
  <BSCreature
   sCreatureName='Su-Monster'
   nAC='6'
   nACBase='6'
   jACMod='0'
   jHitPointLabel='46'
   jClassSelect='4'
   nEXP='650'
   nHonor='-1'
   lAttacks='5'
   nHitPoints='46'
   nLevel='6'
   nToHitRank='7'
   jNotePad=''
   sDescription='SA: Suprise 1-6 on d10\nSD: Immune to psionics.\n'
   sSpecialAttack='N'
   sSpecialDefense='N'
   sMagicDefense='Normal'
   sPSIAttack='N'
   sPSIDefense='N'
   nBASENumAtks='1'
   nBASEMorale='10'
   nBASEMove='12'
   nBASESizeIndex='2'
   nBASEAlignmentIndex='4'
   nBASEHackFactor='1'
   nFatigueFactor='10'
   nCombatRounds='0'
   nCreatureID='1232'
   >
     <Attack
       jWeaponType='0'
       jToHitMod='0'
       jPerDiceMod='0'
       jTotalMod='0'
       jNumDice='1'
       jDiceSides='4'
       jModPenetration='0'
       jModFumble='0'
       jModCrit='0'
     >
     </Attack>
     <Attack
       jWeaponType='0'
       jToHitMod='0'
       jPerDiceMod='0'
       jTotalMod='0'
       jNumDice='1'
       jDiceSides='4'
       jModPenetration='0'
       jModFumble='0'
       jModCrit='0'
     >
     </Attack>
     <Attack
       jWeaponType='0'
       jToHitMod='0'
       jPerDiceMod='0'
       jTotalMod='0'
       jNumDice='1'
       jDiceSides='4'
       jModPenetration='0'
       jModFumble='0'
       jModCrit='0'
     >
     </Attack>
     <Attack
       jWeaponType='0'
       jToHitMod='0'
       jPerDiceMod='0'
       jTotalMod='0'
       jNumDice='1'
       jDiceSides='4'
       jModPenetration='0'
       jModFumble='0'
       jModCrit='0'
     >
     </Attack>
     <Attack
       jWeaponType='0'
       jToHitMod='0'
       jPerDiceMod='0'
       jTotalMod='0'
       jNumDice='2'
       jDiceSides='8'
       jModPenetration='0'
       jModFumble='0'
       jModCrit='0'
     >
     </Attack>
  </BSCreature>
</BattleSheets>
