<?xml version="1.0"?>
<PlayerFile>
  <Player
   lPlayerID='1060970809968'
   sPlayerName='Tony'
   sCharacter='Grog'
   sFamilyClan=''
   sHomeland='NA'
   sGawd='NA'
   sPatron='NA'
   sAppearance=''
   sBirthDate=''
   sFamilyHistory='Celeb Parent, both alive'
   sHairColour='none'
   sEyeColour=''
   sSpecialAbilities=''
   sMiscInfo=''
   sRace='half-ogre'
   jPlayerLog='Saturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2261 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2262 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2263 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2264 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 24 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2288 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2289 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2290 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2291 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2292 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2293 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2294 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2295 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2296 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2297 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2298 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2299 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2300 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2301 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2302 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2303 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2304 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2305 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2306 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2307 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2308 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2309 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2310 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2311 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2312 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2313 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2326 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2339 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2352 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2365 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2378 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2391 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2404 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2417 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2452 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2487 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2522 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2557 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2592 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2627 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2662 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2697 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2732 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2767 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2802 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2837 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2872 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2907 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2942 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 2977 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3012 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3047 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3082 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3095 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3108 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3121 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 24 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3145 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 24 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3169 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3204 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 35 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3239 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3252 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3265 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3278 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 24 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3302 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 130 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3432 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3445 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3458 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 13 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3471 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 200 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3671 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Awarded 200 EXP for Fighter:Precision Cutting, DETAILS: Individual EXP award for Grog crit hit by grog 2 on rats.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 250 points to the Fighter class for a total of 3921 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Awarded 250 EXP for General:Most Damage Dealt in Single Blow, DETAILS: Individual EXP award for Grog grog hit for 19.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 1000 points to the Fighter class for a total of 4921 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Awarded 1000 EXP for General:Generic, DETAILS: 1000 exp for magic detect wand.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 6750 points to the Fighter class for a total of 11671 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Awarded 6750 EXP for General:Generic, DETAILS: treasure gold/magic exp.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 100 points to the Fighter class for a total of 11771 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Awarded 100 EXP for Fighter:CriticalHit suffered, DETAILS: serverity 10.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 100 points to the Fighter class for a total of 11871 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Awarded 100 EXP for Fighter:CriticalHit suffered, DETAILS: conrad sev 10.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Received EXP award of 200 points to the Fighter class for a total of 12071 experience.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Awarded 200 EXP for General:Role Play Award (average), DETAILS: everyone.\nSaturday, August 16, 2003:Awarded 1 temporal honor for Defeated worthy opponent., DETAILS: Rat, Giant#1 defeated:grog.\n*Tuesday, December 16, 2003 GameDate: GYear:560 GMonth:1 GDay:1:Awarded 1 temporal honor for Defeated worthy opponent., DETAILS: Rat, Giant#10 defeated:gully.\n*Tuesday, December 16, 2003 GameDate: GYear:560 GMonth:1 GDay:1:Awarded 1 temporal honor for Defeated worthy opponent., DETAILS: Stirge, Common#9 defeated:grog,sucking.\n*Tuesday, December 16, 2003 GameDate: GYear:560 GMonth:1 GDay:1:Awarded 1 temporal honor for Defeated worthy opponent., DETAILS: Skeleton, Animated#3 defeated:liam,conrad.\n*Tuesday, December 16, 2003 GameDate: GYear:560 GMonth:1 GDay:1:Awarded 1 temporal honor for Defeated worthy opponent., DETAILS: Skeleton, Animated#2 defeated:.\n*Tuesday, December 16, 2003 GameDate: GYear:560 GMonth:1 GDay:1:Awarded 1 temporal honor for Defeated worthy opponent., DETAILS: Rat, Giant#16 defeated:conrad.\n*Tuesday, December 16, 2003 GameDate: GYear:560 GMonth:1 GDay:1:Awarded 1 temporal honor for Defeated worthy opponent., DETAILS: Rat, Giant#20 defeated:liam,lorum,grog.\n*Tuesday, December 16, 2003 GameDate: GYear:560 GMonth:1 GDay:1:Awarded 1 temporal honor for Defeated worthy opponent., DETAILS: Skeleton, Animated#4 defeated:liam,conrad.\n*Tuesday, December 16, 2003 GameDate: GYear:560 GMonth:1 GDay:1:Awarded 1 temporal honor for Defeated worthy opponent., DETAILS: Skeleton, Animated#5 defeated:liam,conrad.\n*Tuesday, December 16, 2003 GameDate: GYear:560 GMonth:1 GDay:1:Awarded 1 temporal honor for Defeated worthy opponent., DETAILS: Rat, Giant#15 defeated:conrad.\n*Tuesday, December 16, 2003 GameDate: GYear:560 GMonth:1 GDay:1:Awarded 1 temporal honor for Defeated worthy opponent., DETAILS: Rat, Giant#4 defeated:grog.\n*Tuesday, December 16, 2003 GameDate: GYear:560 GMonth:1 GDay:1:Awarded 1 temporal honor for Defeated worthy opponent., DETAILS: Rat, Giant#5 defeated:grog.\n*Tuesday, December 16, 2003 GameDate: GYear:560 GMonth:1 GDay:1:Awarded 1 temporal honor for Defeated worthy opponent., DETAILS: Rat, Giant#9 defeated:gully.\n*Tuesday, December 16, 2003 GameDate: GYear:560 GMonth:1 GDay:1:Honor adjusted: 13/4+18=21\n'
   nBirthRank='8'
   nAge='17'
   nHeight='90'
   nWeight='395'
   nSocialClassIndex='5'
   nNumberSiblings='7'
   nHandIndex='1'
   nAlignementIndex='7'
   nSexIndex='0'
   nAIP='0'
   jSizeComboBox='3'
   AC_NORMAL='4'
   AC_REAR='4'
   AC_SHIELDLESS='4'
   AC_SUPRISED='6'
   jHealthMax='63'
   jHealthLabel='63'
   jMove='9'
   jHonor='21'
   nTemporalHonor='0'
   >
         <Abilities
         sName='Strength'
         jAdjScore='21'
         jAdjPercent='9'
          >
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Hit Probability'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='4'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Damage Adjustment'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='9'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Weight Allowance'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='600'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Max Press'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='810'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Open Doors'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='17(12)'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Bend Bars/Lift Gates'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='70%'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
         </Abilities>
         <Abilities
         sName='Dexterity'
         jAdjScore='16'
         jAdjPercent='35'
          >
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Defense Adjustment'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='-2'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Reaction Adjustment'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='+3'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Missle Adjustment'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='+3'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
         </Abilities>
         <Abilities
         sName='Constitution'
         jAdjScore='24'
         jAdjPercent='99'
          >
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Hit Point Adjustment'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='+7'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='System Shock'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='99%'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Ressurection Survival'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='100%'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Poison Save'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='+3'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Immunity to Disease/Alchohol'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='-95%'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Regeneration'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='1 HP/2 turns'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
         </Abilities>
         <Abilities
         sName='Intelligence'
         jAdjScore='9'
         jAdjPercent='3'
          >
             <AbilityMods
             sName='# of Languages'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='2'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Spell Level'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='4th'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Learning Ability'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='35%'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Max # Spells Per Level'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='6'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Illusion Immunity'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='-'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Chance of Spell Mishap'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='20%'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
         </Abilities>
         <Abilities
         sName='Wisdom'
         jAdjScore='8'
         jAdjPercent='87'
          >
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Magical Adjustment'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='0'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Bonus Spells'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='0'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Chance of Spell Failure'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='25%'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Spell Immunity'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='-'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Chance to Improve Skill'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='04%'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
         </Abilities>
         <Abilities
         sName='Charisma'
         jAdjScore='11'
         jAdjPercent='98'
          >
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Max # of Henchmen/Cronies/SideKicks'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='4'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Loyalty Base'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='0'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Reaction Adjustment'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='0'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Comeliness Modifier'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='0'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Starting Honor Modifier'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='0'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
         </Abilities>
         <Abilities
         sName='Comeliness'
         jAdjScore='8'
         jAdjPercent='32'
          >
             <AbilityMods
             sName='Special'
             nMod='-1'
             jMod='Homely looking.'
             >
             </AbilityMods>
         </Abilities>
         <Class
         sName='Fighter'
         nClassindex='0'
         nClassID='0'
         nSaveAs='0'
         nFightAs='0'
         jLevel='2'
         jEXP='7999'
          >
         </Class>
         <Saves
         sName='Paralyzation, Poison, Death Magic'
         nSaveType='0'
         nBaseSave='14'
         jSave='14'
         jSaveMod='0'
         jSaveOther='0'
          >
         </Saves>
         <Saves
         sName='Rod, Staff, Wand'
         nSaveType='1'
         nBaseSave='16'
         jSave='16'
         jSaveMod='0'
         jSaveOther='0'
          >
         </Saves>
         <Saves
         sName='Petrifaction, HackFrenzy, HackLust, PolyMorph'
         nSaveType='2'
         nBaseSave='15'
         jSave='15'
         jSaveMod='0'
         jSaveOther='0'
          >
         </Saves>
         <Saves
         sName='Breath Weapon'
         nSaveType='3'
         nBaseSave='18'
         jSave='18'
         jSaveMod='0'
         jSaveOther='0'
          >
         </Saves>
         <Saves
         sName='Apology'
         nSaveType='4'
         nBaseSave='18'
         jSave='18'
         jSaveMod='0'
         jSaveOther='0'
          >
         </Saves>
         <Saves
         sName='Spells'
         nSaveType='5'
         nBaseSave='17'
         jSave='17'
         jSaveMod='0'
         jSaveOther='0'
          >
         </Saves>
         <Coins
         sName='Copper'
         jCount='0'
          >
         </Coins>
         <Coins
         sName='Silver'
         jCount='0'
          >
         </Coins>
         <Coins
         sName='Electrum'
         jCount='0'
          >
         </Coins>
         <Coins
         sName='Gold'
         jCount='0'
          >
         </Coins>
         <Coins
         sName='Hardsilver'
         jCount='0'
          >
         </Coins>
         <Coins
         sName='Platinum'
         jCount='0'
          >
         </Coins>
         <Gear
         sName='armor:hide'
         sDesc='hide armor'
         sLoc='body'
         nCount='1'
         dWeight='35.0'
         nGearID='2'
          >
         </Gear>
         <Gear
         sName='container:backpack'
         sDesc='backpack'
         sLoc='back'
         nCount='1'
         dWeight='2.0'
         nGearID='3'
          >
         </Gear>
         <Gear
         sName='clothing:robe'
         sDesc='robe'
         sLoc='backpack'
         nCount='1'
         dWeight='2.0'
         nGearID='2'
          >
         </Gear>
         <Gear
         sName='clothing:cloak'
         sDesc='simple cloak'
         sLoc='back'
         nCount='1'
         dWeight='2.0'
         nGearID='5'
          >
         </Gear>
         <Gear
         sName='equipment:rope, hemp 50&apos;'
         sDesc='50 foot of hemp rope'
         sLoc='backpack'
         nCount='1'
         dWeight='20.0'
         nGearID='6'
          >
         </Gear>
         <Gear
         sName='provisions:wineskin'
         sDesc='wineskin, 1 gallon of liquid'
         sLoc='backpack'
         nCount='1'
         dWeight='1.0'
         nGearID='2'
          >
         </Gear>
         <Skills
         sName='tasks:mundane:armor maintenance'
         sDesc='able to perform basic maintenance on armor'
         jSkillSpinner='1'
         nSkillID='13'
         nSkillType='0'
          >
         </Skills>
         <Skills
         sName='tasks:mundane:weapon maintenance'
         sDesc='able to perform basic maintenance on weapons'
         jSkillSpinner='1'
         nSkillID='14'
         nSkillType='0'
          >
         </Skills>
         <Skills
         sName='launguage:common'
         sDesc='skilled speaking common'
         jSkillSpinner='100'
         nSkillID='12'
         nSkillType='0'
          >
         </Skills>
         <Skills
         sName='tasks:sophisticated:swimming: dogpaddle'
         sDesc='able to dog paddle'
         jSkillSpinner='38'
         nSkillID='15'
         nSkillType='0'
          >
         </Skills>
         <Skills
         sName='tasks:sophisticated:cooking'
         sDesc='able to cook'
         jSkillSpinner='23'
         nSkillID='16'
         nSkillType='0'
          >
         </Skills>
         <Skills
         sName='tasks:sophisticated:map sense'
         sDesc='look up description'
         jSkillSpinner='27'
         nSkillID='17'
         nSkillType='0'
          >
         </Skills>
         <Skills
         sName='tasks:sophisticated:rope use'
         sDesc='able to use ropes and tie knots.'
         jSkillSpinner='39'
         nSkillID='18'
         nSkillType='0'
          >
         </Skills>
         <Skills
         sName='endurance'
         sDesc='a character with endurance is able to perform continual physical activity for twice as long as normal character.'
         jSkillSpinner='1'
         nSkillID='19'
         nSkillType='1'
          >
         </Skills>
         <Skills
         sName='damage bonus'
         sDesc='+1 damage with a single weapon of the characters choice.'
         jSkillSpinner='1'
         nSkillID='20'
         nSkillType='1'
          >
         </Skills>
         <Skills
         sName='dense skin'
         sDesc='character with this talent takes 1/2 damage from blunt weapons'
         jSkillSpinner='1'
         nSkillID='22'
         nSkillType='1'
          >
         </Skills>
         <Skills
         sName='tough hide'
         sDesc='Character has a natural AC of 8. If the character wears armor that would improve his AC better than 8 this ability has no effect. If the character wears armor that give him an ac of 8 or worse he may add +1 bonus to his AC.'
         jSkillSpinner='1'
         nSkillID='23'
         nSkillType='1'
          >
         </Skills>
         <Skills
         sName='infra vision, 30ft'
         sDesc='see in the infra spectrum for 30ft.'
         jSkillSpinner='1'
         nSkillID='24'
         nSkillType='3'
          >
         </Skills>
         <Quirks
         sName='minor physical:scar, facial'
         sDesc='look up description and update'
         nQuirkID='10'
          >
         </Quirks>
         <Quirks
         sName='minor physical:strange body odor'
         sDesc='look up description and update'
         nQuirkID='11'
          >
         </Quirks>
  </Player>
</PlayerFile>
